What happens after happily ever after?
Shrek 2 is a animation, family, comedy film directed by Conrad Vernon.
Shrek, Fiona, and Donkey set off to Far, Far Away to meet
Fiona's mother and father, the Queen and King.
But not everyone is happily ever after, as Shrek and
the King find it difficult to get along.
But when the Fairy Godmother discovers that Fiona has married Shrek instead of her son Prince Charming as King
Harold had promised, she plots to destroy their marriage and replace the ogre with her son Charming.
Shrek (voice), played by Mike Myers.
Donkey (voice), played by Eddie Murphy.
Princess Fiona (voice), played by Cameron Diaz.
Queen Lillian (voice), played by Julie Andrews.
Puss in Boots (voice), played by Antonio Banderas.
King Harold (voice), played by John Cleese.
Shrek 2 is a 2004 American animated fantasy comedy film loosely
based on the 1990 children's picture book Shrek!
by William Steig.
Directed by Andrew Adamson, Kelly Asbury, and Conrad Vernon from a
screenplay by Adamson, Joe Stillman, and the writing team of J.
David Stem and David N.
Weiss, it is the sequel to Shrek (2001) and the second
installment in the Shrek film series.
The film stars Mike Myers, Eddie Murphy, and Cameron Diaz, who reprise their
respective voice roles of Shrek, Donkey, and Princess Fiona.
They are joined by new characters voiced by Antonio Banderas, Julie
Andrews, John Cleese, Rupert Everett, and Jennifer Saunders.
Shrek 2 takes place following the events of the first film, with Shrek and Donkey meeting Fiona's parents as the zealous
Fairy Godmother, who wants Fiona to marry her son Prince Charming, plots to destroy Shrek and Fiona's marriage.
Shrek and Donkey team up with a sword-wielding cat
named Puss in Boots to foil her plans.
Development began in 2001, and following disagreements with producers, the first film's
screenwriters Ted Elliott and Terry Rossio were replaced with Adamson.
The story was inspired by Guess Who's Coming to Dinner (1967), and new animation tools were
utilized to improve the visual appearance of each character, particularly Puss in Boots.
The lead actors also received a significant bump in salary to $10 million, which at
the time was among the highest contracts in their respective careers.
Like its predecessor, Shrek 2 also parodies other films based on fairy
tales and features references to American popular culture.
The film is dedicated to the memory of Shrek creator William Steig, who died
on October 3, 2003, seven months before the film was released.
Shrek 2 premiered at the 2004 Cannes Film Festival on May 15, 2004, where it competed for the
Palme d'Or, and was released in theaters on May 19, by DreamWorks Pictures.
Like its predecessor, it received positive reviews from critics and is
considered by many to be one of the best sequel films ever made.
The film grossed $933.8 million worldwide, and scored the second-largest three-day opening weekend in
United States history and the largest opening for an animated film at the time of its release.
It went on to become the highest-grossing film of 2004 and the
fourth-highest-grossing film overall at the time of its release.
Shrek 2 is also DreamWorks Animation's highest-grossing film to date and the highest-grossing film released by DreamWorks Pictures, and it held the
title of being the highest-grossing animated film of all time worldwide until Pixar Animation Studios' Toy Story 3 surpassed it in 2010.
The film received two Academy Award nominations for Best Animated Feature and Best Original
Song, and its associated soundtrack charted in the Top 10 on the US Billboard 200.
Two sequels—Shrek the Third (2007) and Shrek Forever After (2010)—had soon followed,
with an upcoming sequel, Shrek 5, scheduled to be released in June 2027.
The film's character Puss in Boots has also received his own series of spin-off media—Puss in Boots (2011), The
Adventures of Puss in Boots (2015–2018), and Puss in Boots: The Last Wish (2022)—following his debut.
The film explores themes of prison, princess, magic, kingdom, fairy tale.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.